stampworld.com 2007-12-17

# Collectors.com -- The Ultimate Collectors Destination --

### Privacy Statement for Collectors Universe

_Last Modified June 30, 2005_

Collectors Universe, Inc. (“CU” or “we”) has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering, use and dissemination practices for this website. Please take a moment to review the terms of this privacy statement. By using this site, you agree to accept the terms of our privacy statement. If you do not agree to the terms of our privacy statement, please do not use this site. Unless stated otherwise, this privacy statement applies only to information collected on this site and does not apply to information that we may collect by other means.

#### Personal Information

_**Information We May Collect**_

You are not required to provide any personal information in order to obtain general access to this site. However, in order to access certain information, products, services or features contained on this site, we may require you to provide personal information such as your name, e-mail address, mailing address and phone number. For example, we will collect certain personal information if you choose to apply for a Collectors Club Membership, subscribe to one of our magazines, sign up for our set registry service, join one of our message boards, enter into a contest on this site or send questions or comments to us via e-mail. For those products and services offered on this site for which we require a membership, subscription or other fee or charge, we will also collect certain financial information such as credit card number and shipping and billing addresses.

If you choose to post messages in our message boards, chat rooms or other message areas or leave feedback for other users, we may collect such information about you as you choose to disclose in such forums. Likewise, if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on our message boards or other areas of this site, we may collect such information into a file specific to you. CU may keep a log of inactive account information for an indefinite period of time, in CU’s discretion. 

_**How We May Use Your Information**_

If you provide us with personal information, we may retain and use that information for several purposes. For example, we may use your personal information in order to process and fulfill any transactions or services that you request, such as delivering any products and services that you purchase on this site (including any customary follow-up or confirmation communications regarding such transactions), contacting you in connection with a contest that you have entered, e-mailing our online newsletter or online magazines to you if you are a subscriber or responding to your questions and comments. We may also use personal information to ensure compliance with our policies and applicable law. 

In addition, we may send you periodic communications by e-mail or regular mail if you do not opt out of receiving them. For example, we may provide you with special offers or information on our products or services. If you wish to opt out of receiving communications from us at any time, we give users the following options for doing so:

  1. Where available, you may indicate that you do not want to receive such mailings at the time you provide your information to us on this site; 
  2. You may opt-out at any time by sending an email to [customerservice@collectors.com](mailto:customerservice@collectors.com) with “unsubscribe” in the subject line; or 
  3. You may opt-out by clicking on the unsubscribe link in our email newsletters or other email communications. 

_**Disclosure of Personal Information**_

Please note that we will not share your personal information (whether collected online or offline) with any third parties for their direct marketing purposes. 

We may sometimes use other businesses to perform certain services for us, such as processing orders and delivering our products, sending postal mail and providing marketing assistance and data analysis. We may provide personal information to those businesses when that information is necessary for them to complete a requested transaction or otherwise perform their duties. 

As CU develops, we may buy other businesses or their assets or sell our business assets. Customer information is generally one of the business assets involved in such transactions. Thus, in the event that CU or one of its divisions, or all of their respective assets, are acquired, customer information would be one of the transferred assets. 

Finally, we reserve the right to disclose visitor information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property, other visitors, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. This includes our right to exchange information with other organizations in order to protect against fraud and to reduce credit risk. We also reserve the right to disclose visitor information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it. 

#### Message Boards and Other Public Forums

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please keep in mind that whenever you give out personal information on a message board or other “public” forum, that information can be collected and used by people you don’t know. If you choose to voluntarily disclose information on a message board, chat room or other public forum on this site, this privacy statement will not cover such disclosure of information. We urge you to use caution when disclosing any personal information on these venues. For additional terms and rules regarding the use of our message boards, please see our message boards Terms of Membership. 

#### Links to Other Sites

The message boards and other areas of this site contain links to other sites that take you outside this site. These outside sites are beyond our control. They may send their own cookies to visitors, collect data or solicit personal information. The privacy policies of these other sites may be significantly different from our privacy statement. We will not notify you when you are leaving our site and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these other sites and cannot guarantee the security of any of your personal information collected there. 

#### Aggregate Information

From time to time, we may collect general, non-personal, statistical information about the use of this site, such as how many visitors visit a specific page on this site, how long they stay on that page, and which hyperlinks, if any, they “click” on. We collect this information through the use of technologies such as “cookies” and “IP addresses”, which are discussed in greater detail below. We collect this information in order to determine which areas of this site are most popular and to enhance this site for visitors. We may also group this and other information into aggregate visitor data in order to describe the use of this site to our existing or potential business partners, sponsors, advertisers or other third parties, or in response to a government request. However, please be assured that this aggregate data will in no way personally identify you or any other visitors to this site. 

#### IP Addresses and Cookies

In the course of using our site, we automatically track certain information about you. This information includes the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our site or not), what browser you are using, and your IP address (which is a number that’s automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web). Many sites automatically collect this information. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our site. Your IP address is used to help identify you and your shopping cart. We reserve the right to use IP addresses to identify a visitor when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with this site’s policies or to protect our service or customers, this site, or others. 

Like most websites, our site does use cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to an individual’s hard drive for record-keeping purposes. In some cases the cookies are linked to your personally identifiable information. Cookies are used to simplify functions on our website for our users. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, please be aware that some features of this site may not function properly or may be slower if you refuse cookies. You may occasionally get cookies from our advertisers or other third parties with links on this site. We do not control these cookies. The use of advertising cookies sent by third-party servers is standard in the Internet industry. 

#### Children Under 13

We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 on this site. If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide any personal information to us. 

#### Changes to These Terms

The terms of this privacy statement may change from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes to this privacy statement by posting a notice on the homepage of this site, for a reasonable period of time after such changes are made, that this privacy statement has been updated, and by changing the “Last Modified” date at the top of this privacy statement. We encourage you to check this page periodically for any changes. Your continued use of this site following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. 

#### Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. If you register for certain of our services, such as a Collectors Club Membership, our message boards or our set registry service, you will be required to create an online account and choose a username and password that will protect your online account information. Access to your online account requires your password. We recommend that you do not disclose your username or password to any other person. In addition, all credit card information is accessed only through secure servers using SSL encryption for the protection of our customers. Credit card information is not stored and is discarded between usages. All databases are secured behind a firewall. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while CU strives to protect your personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to us online and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction, or inadvertent disclosure of your personal information. 

#### Reviewing and Updating Your Information

If you register for an account on the Site (other than a message boards account), you may review and update your account information by logging in to your account with your username and password at <http://www.collectors.com/join/update.chtml>. If you join our message boards, you may review and update your message board profile information by first logging in to our message boards and then going to <http://forums.collectors.com/profile.cfm>. 

#### Questions

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, you can contact: 

Collectors Universe P.O. Box 6280 Newport Beach, CA 92658 USA [**customerservice@collectors.com**](mailto:customerservice@collectors.com)
